ORAWAN RABAMPHO orabampho@outlook.com

Objectives

I seek a Telecommunications Specialist position where I can demonstrate my leadership abilities and networking knowledge to help diagnose, troubleshoot, and improve existing communications systems; to work for an organization that has unlimited potential for learning and growth.

Availability: Immediately

Summary of Qualifications

Over 20 years of military experience, training, and coordinating on multiple military and commercial communications systems. These systems include Tactical Satellite communications and UHF, VHF, SHF radio systems. Responsible for planning, developing, monitoring, troubleshooting, and coordinating the Division's terrestrial radio systems; provided recommendations and assistance to the Division Staff and Commanders on radio network planning; identifies and de-conflicts frequency interference; conducted spectral site analysis; monitors and reports incidents of interference in a multinational coalition environment; prepares, submits to higher, and tracks Joint Spectrum Interference Reports; Maintains files and records of radio station licenses, authorizations, assignments, and related correspondence, and ensure that necessary action (modification, renewal, etc.) are taken. Applies knowledge of NTIA and FCC regulations and procedures when providing program support. Reviews, access, evaluate, and provide recommendations for proposed equipment to ensure supportability for compliance with Host Nation and government policy.

EXPERIENCE

United States Air Force (USAF) Spectrum Operations, Edwards AFB, CA and Joint Task Force

Dec 2013 to Feb 2021

412th Test Wing, Edwards AFB, CA

Served as the Non-Commissioned Officer in Charge (NCOIC) at Edwards Air Force Base, Assistant Installation Spectrum Manager (ISM) for the 412th Test Wing, and Operations Section Lead for Edwards Air Force Base and the Air Force Test Center (AFTC); responsible for providing electromagnetic spectrum management and frequency control to ensure an interference-free electromagnetic environment in and around the AFTC, the National Test Range R-2508, the USAF Plant 42, and five special DoD-contracted test facilities in the surrounding area. Ensures organizational request for new equipment is in compliance with national, state, and local compliance and specifications prior to purchase. Maintains files and records of radio station licenses, authorizations, assignments, related correspondence, and ensures that necessary actions (modification, renewal, deletions, etc.) are taken using Spectrum XXI. Creates new frequency proposals and submits 5-year reviews of existing assignments for continued use in the AFTC operating area using Spectrum XXI while following the guidelines described in the Military Communications-Electronics Board (MCEB) Publication 7. Schedules and de-conflicts frequencies using the Integrated Frequency Deconfliction System (IFDS). Reviews and evaluates all proposed incoming programs documentation for supportability and spectrum availability to ensure that it will not have an adverse effect to the AFTC by causing unwanted interference to exist programs. Represents the AFTC at Range Commander's Counsel Frequency Management Group (RCC-FMG) meetings, ensuring that the AFTC assets and concerns are addressed to the other range members. Directly monitors and evaluates the RF natural resources for the AFTC. Using various Antennas and Spectrum analyzers, I measure RF signals to ensure/enforce emission compliance and bandwidth requirements as stated on DoD Form DD-1494 and approved by the National Telecommunication

and Information Administration (NTIA). Analyzes signals received to ensure ideal transmissions for mission success. Recommends technical solutions to project engineers to assist in the correction of less than ideal transmissions. Using direction-finding equipment, Spectrum Analyzers, and Oscilloscopes track down unauthorized RF transmissions to minimize the chance of RF interference. Analyzes spectrum utilization and collaborates with my supervisor in developing better policies for the conservation and protection of the RF natural resource. Operates Frequency Control and Analysis (FCA) facility to establish procedures, determine the appropriate measurement systems to utilize, analyze results, and recommends actions be taken or initiates actions to resolve problems and/or encounters in the daily measurement of RF spectrum usage by the Department of Defense (DoD) activities, NASA, and contractors within the area of the AFTC. Employs various special purpose receivers, recorders, RF Direction Finders, and associated antenna systems to analyze and determine the location of unknown Radio Frequency (RF) radiations. Maintains a real-time log and/or recording of all signals detected. Reviews Weekly Aircraft Utilization and Requirements Schedule for radio frequency usage.

NCOIC Spectrum Manager, Joint Task Force

- Served as the Joint Task Force Spectrum/Frequency Manager and Frequency Interference Technician.
- Applied engineering principles and disciplines to the resolution of E3 (Electromagnetic Environment Effects), Electromagnetic Compatibility (EMC), interference, spectrum management, and radio frequency (RF) issues relating to the development, fielding, and operation of commercial and DoD systems. Responsible for integrating incoming equipment, ensuring it is Host Nation compliant and non-interfering.

NCOIC Knowledge Operations, Schriever AFB, CO, 2010 to 2013

- Supervised four members team in executing knowledge operation procedures of 50th Operations Group.
- Responsibilities included Operations group's content manager, provides guidance and ensures updates to the group's private and public web page.
- Functional Area Records Manager (FARM) ensures paper/electronic records are maintained in accordance with regulations and policies.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

United States Air Force, 2001 to 2021

Information/Workgroup Manager

- Manages hardware and software for desktop systems and a file server; perform configuration, management, and initial diagnostics of information system.
- Monitors suspense, including awards, decorations, personnel evaluations, executive level memorandum for timely submissions.

Personnel Supervision/Training

- Supervised, trained, counseled, and evaluated the performance of 4 assigned personnel.
- Provided personal and professional counseling to subordinates to enhance career development.
- Coordinated workflow and allocations; effectively managed time; assigned work to subordinates.

SPECIALIZED TRAINING

- Spectrum XXI June 2013
- System Planning Engineering Evaluation Device (SPEED) June 2013
- Equipment Location-Certification Information Database (EL-CID) June 2013
- Spectrum Management Course (Keesler AFB, MS) -10 Weeks
- Professional Military Education
 - USAF Senior NCO Academy (Online) 2017
 - Non-Commissioned Officer Academy 2014
 - Airman Leadership School 2005

EDUCATION

2015	Associate Degree Information Resources Management
2015	Associate Degree Information Systems Management